Backend Developer

PROFILE

Experienced back-end developer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Python (Django), PHP(Laravel), C++, Java, Back-End Web Development, and REST API. I graduated from Computer and Information Asyut, University.

CONTACT

+201010079798

Asyut, Eygpt

hosamameen948@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/hossamameen97/

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native

English: Intermediate

EDUCATION

Assuit University, 2020

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology

SKILLS

Programing languages:

Python,PHP,Java,C++,Javascript

Web framework:

Django and Laravel

Database:

MySQL and Postgres

DevOps:

Cloud:

Docker and CI/CD

AWS and Digital Ocean

Web technology:

HTML, CSS, JS and bootstrap

Source control:

Git and Github

Operation system: Ubuntu and windows

Hossam Mohamed

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Midlevel-back-end developer | Shipblu technology

Jan. 2022 - present

- Conduct code reviews for Pull Requests (PR) submitted by fellow developers, ensuring adherence to coding standards, best practices, and project requirements.
- Identify and troubleshoot issues within the codebase.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to implement updates, scale the project, and introduce new features.
- Introduce unit testing strategies to improve code quality and enhance the robustness of the software.

Freelancer back-end developer | Axes digital agency

Sept. 2018 - Oct. 2019

- Led the development of a personal website, taking ownership of the entire backend architecture and ensuring optimal performance.
- Designed and implemented a comprehensive dashboard system to efficiently manage and control website data, enhancing user experience and data management capabilities.
- Developed and maintained robust APIs to facilitate seamless communication between the back-end and front-end, contributing to a cohesive and responsive website.

Junior Back-end developer | Zedy digital agency

Jan. 2021 - Jan. 2022

- Led the development of a personal website, taking ownership of the entire backend architecture and ensuring optimal performance.
- Designed and implemented a comprehensive dashboard system to efficiently manage and control website data, enhancing user experience and data management capabilities.
- Developed and maintained robust APIs to facilitate seamless communication between the back-end and front-end, contributing to a cohesive and responsive website.

PROJECTS

egypal.fr

- Developed and implemented back-end APIs for Egypal.fr, a company services showcase website in Europe.
- Designed a user-friendly dashboard API, enabling efficient data management for the client.
- Facilitated seamless integration of APIs, contributing to a responsive and cohesive website.
- Achieved optimal performance in processing client orders and handling contact requests.

slashsolutions.net

- Implemented back-end APIs for slashsolutions.net, a project for a digital agency company.
- Constructed APIs to enhance website functionality and support data management for a user-friendly dashboard.
- Successfully contributed to the project's overall success by providing robust backend solutions for both the website and dashboard.

goda-dent.com

- Implemented back-end APIs goda-dent.com, a project for a dent doctor.
- Constructed APIs to enhance website functionality and support data management for a user-friendly dashboard.
- Successfully contributed to the project's overall success by providing robust backend solutions for both the website and dashboard.